<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>data structures on Mostly Technical</title><link>https://balta2ar.github.io/tags/data-structures/</link><description>Recent content in data structures on Mostly Technical</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 16:03:18 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://balta2ar.github.io/tags/data-structures/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Segment Trees for overlapping intervals</title><link>https://balta2ar.github.io/posts/2022-12-31-segment-trees-intervals/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 16:03:18 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://balta2ar.github.io/posts/2022-12-31-segment-trees-intervals/</guid><description>Segment trees are a data structure that can be used for a variety of problems. Usually, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen them used for range queries, but they can also be used for finding overlapping intervals.
When applied to the problem of answering range queries (e.g. sum on an interval), the key idea with segment trees is to split the problem space into smaller parts during preprocessing, so that during query we can visit only a small part of the problem space.</description></item><item><title>Вопросы на собеседовании из курса Algorithms</title><link>https://balta2ar.github.io/posts/2009-09-29-algorithms-interview-questions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2009 16:03:18 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://balta2ar.github.io/posts/2009-09-29-algorithms-interview-questions/</guid><description>Вопросы на собеседовании из курса Algorithms Заканчивается первая часть курса Algorithms на coursera.org. Это был один из немногих курсов, в котором мне понравилось абсолютно всё: прекрасная подача материала (лектор — сам Седжвик), наглядные слайды, наличие сопутствующей курсу книги, из которой можно почерпнуть больше подробностей по теме, нетривиальные домашние задания и, наконец, вопросы для интервью.
Я первый раз вижу, чтобы в курсе давали примеры таких вопросов. Это отличное подспорье для подготовки к собеседованиям, и поэтому я хочу поделиться ими здесь.</description></item></channel></rss>